# Tareq Aghabi

+971 (52) 522 9094 | taregaghabi@gmail.com | LinkedIn

## **PROFILE**

Senior Data Analyst and Industrial Engineer with 5+ years of experience in Advanced Data Analytics, Development & Modeling, Visualization, Engineering, Supply Chain & Logistics Operations, Upstream and Downstream Retail & Distribution, proficient in SQL, LookML, Google BigQuery, PowerBI, Python, R and Excel. Canadian and Jordanian citizen, native in English and Arabic.

## **EDUCATION**

**Georgia Tech University,** School of Computational Science and Engineering Master of Science in Analytics (MSc)

Atlanta, GA

January 2023

Relevant Coursework: Data Science in Business, Machine Learning, ETL, Analytics Modeling, Web Development

## International Federation of Purchasing and Supply Management IFPSM,

Dubai, UAE

Certified Advanced Supply Chain Professional (CASP)

November 2022

Relevant Coursework: Cost Analysis, Planning, Forecasting, Sourcing, Warehousing, Inventory Management, Logistics

#### Harvard University, School of Engineering and Applied Sciences

HarvardX

Professional Certificate in Data Science (PCert)

February 2021

• Relevant Coursework: SQL, Python, R, Visualization, Probability, Wrangling, Regression, Machine Learning & AI

Concordia University, School of Engineering and Computer Science

Montréal, QC

Bachelor of Science in Industrial Engineering (BEng)

May 2019

• Relevant Coursework: Operations Research, Stochastic Models, Simulation, Calculus, Probability & Statistics

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Chalhoub Group - Largest luxury goods retailer and distributor in MENA

Dubai, UAE

Senior Data Analyst - Supply Chain Central Team – Managed Companies Management

January 2022 – Present

- Worked alongside the Chief Demand and Supply Planning Officer as part of the Central Supply Chain Management and
  drove the Group's upstream and downstream strategic direction by establishing executive, management, and operational
  reporting and prescriptive analysis on fifteen global retail and distribution business entities of over 1000 unique brands.
- Managed and guided a team of six Supply Chain Data Analysts on database modeling and developing over a hundred KPIs and Looker BI dashboards used by executive-level management to periodically track sales, stock, coverage, service levels, fulfillment rate, weekly trade, warehouse lead time, vendor & supplier performance, returns and e-comm supply chain. Improving standardized visibility by 100% and delivering actionable insights to key stakeholders company-wide.
- Engineered, simulated, and merged 50TB of supply chain data using Google BigQuery, SQL, and Looker, creating descriptive, diagnostic, predictive, and prescriptive analytics on an item, market, department, vendor, and brand level, such as Root Cause Analysis on on-shelf availability, upstream & downstream fill rate and coverage statistical analysis.
- Governed Supply Chain KPIs and Dashboards as a data steward, authorizing over 250 GitHub LookML data merges from the Supply Chain Data Analyst community, maintaining supply chain data governance to 100%.
- Optimized query performance by developing LookML derived and aggregate tables, decreasing query cost by 55TB, increasing dashboard speed, and improving user experience.
- Organized and hosted two offsites for supply chain leaders, senior managers, and data analysts on supply chain KPI
  alignment and organized a dashboard-building competition in which I built the highest-ranking dashboard with a
  performance score of over 100%.

## <u>Goodfood Market Corporation</u> – Canada-wide online grocery delivery

Montréal, QC

Operations Analyst – Big Data Analytics & Supply Chain Operations

August 2020 – January 2022

- Promoted to Operations Analyst within eight months for exceeding goals and supporting company culture.
- Configured the weekly system changeover for over 1500 new SKU items in the Goodfood E-commerce backend database and ERP warehouse management system, determining multi-facility SKU picking & storage locations and inventory replenishment triggers based on analysis of order volume projections and operations cost analysis.
- Automated customer order data pull schedules from Looker into Google Sheets to develop an interfacility inventory replenishment analysis model using JavaScript, improving item replenishment availability and visibility by 50%.
- Strategically assigned over 3000 multi-facility SKU storage and picked location data into the Goodfood E-commerce backend database and ERP warehouse management system using Microsoft SQL Server Studio queries.
- Created over ten automated analysis tools and visualization dashboards for logging short ship data, managing labor cost, and tracking shipping carrier progress, providing daily item management decisions to senior directors and executives.

## **United Parcel Service (UPS)** – Global shipping & logistics

Montréal, QC

Industrial Engineering Specialist – Route Optimization Engineering Project Team

April 2019 - May 2020

- Utilized proprietary mapping and optimization software to plot and schedule delivery route information for over 70 training and verification rides on deployed driver groups, decreasing route delivery mileage by 15%.
- Extracted and manipulated route-specific statistics stored in UPS proprietary databases using Excel Visual Basic to generate over 25 technical reports, providing corporate-wide visibility to overall project deployment progress.
- Optimized and scheduled over 1800 driver and helper meetups in all regions of Montréal and Laval using UPS logistics software, resulting in an increase of 70 stops per package car during peak season.
- Created a Master Operating Plan for the Data Acquisition department documenting the data collection and transformation methods for package processing at UPS, standardizing data processing operations and decreasing errors by 25%.